A Guide to the Fairfax Harrison collection, 1730-1931
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Fairfax Harrison collection, 1730-1931
The Library of Virginia
22166
12.225 cu. ft. and 33 boxes
Fairfax Harrison
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Mrs. Charles Baird, Jr., of Marshall, Virginia.
Biographical Information
The son of Burton Norvell Harrison (1838-1904) and Constance Cary Harrison (1843-1920), Fairfax Harrison was born 13 March 1869 in New York, New York. He received his A.B. from Yale University in 1891 and his Master's of Arts from Columbia University in 1892. Admitted to the New York bar in 1892, Harrison became a solicitor for the Southern Railway in 1896. In 1906, he became a vice-president, and in 1913, president of the Southern Railway, retiring in 1937. Harrison served as vice-president of the Virginia Historical Society and as chairman of the committee overseeing the compilation of the Index of Virginia by Earl G. Swem (1870-1965). Harrison also wrote several histories on Virginia, including works on the Northern Neck, on horses and horse racing, and the Harrison and Cary families. Harrison married Hetty Cary (1871-1943) 6 June 1894. Harrison died 2 February 1938.
Scope and Content
Collection, ca. 1730-1931, of Fairfax Harrison (1869-1938) consisting mainly of extensive notes concerning race horses in America, 1730-1834, including data on importation, breeding, racing, and other aspects. These notes were collected by Fairfax Harrison and his agents from various sources, in particular from newspapers. Collection also includes transcripts or photocopies of the original items, in addition to relevant notes by Harrison. There are genealogical notes on Virginia families associated with race horses.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I: Horses
Series II: Individuals and families
Series III: Advertisements
Racing
Publications
Correspondence
General files
Oversize
Contents List
- Series I: Horses., Extent: 18 boxes. (Box 1-18)
  - Charon. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Childers [Flying Childers]. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Creeper. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Dragon. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Dutchess. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Eclipse. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Gimcrack. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - The Godolpin [Arabian]. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - The Godolphin Arabian. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Godolphin mare. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Lexington and Boston. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - The Lexington pedigree. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - [Shepherd's] Lightfoot. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Mary Grey's pedigree. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Matchem. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Mosco's Arabian. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - The Narragansett Pacer. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Selim. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Selima. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Silk Strings. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Sir Archy. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Timoleon. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Charon, Crab, Janus, Wildair, Arabian Bellsize. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Virginia horses, 1740-1764. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Virginia horses, 1765-1770. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Virginia horses, 1771-1776 (folder 1 of 2). (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Virginia horses, 1771-1776 (folder 2 of 2). (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Virginia horses, 1777-1778 (folder 1 of 2). (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Virginia horses, 1777-1778 (folder 2 of 2). (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Virginia horses, 1779-1781 (folder 1 of 2). (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Virginia horses, 1779-1781 (folder 2 of 2). (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Virginia horses, 1782-1789 (folder 1 of 2). (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Virginia horses, 1782-1789 (folder 2 of 2). (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Virginia horses, 1790-1793. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Virginia horses, 1794. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Virginia horses, 1795. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Virginia horses, 1796. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Virginia horses, 1797-1799 (folder 1 of 2). (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Virginia horses, 1797-1799 (folder 2 of 2). (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Virginia horses, 1800-1805 (folder 1 of 2). (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Virginia horses, 1800-1805 (folder 2 of 2). (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Virginia horses, 1806-1809. (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Virginia horses, 1810-1820 (folder 1 of 2). (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Virginia horses, 1810-1820 (folder 2 of 2). (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Virginia horses, 1820-. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Virginia horses--index, 1761-1830. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Virginia horses--index, 1764-1825 (folder 1 of 2). (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Virginia horses--index, 1764-1825 (folder 2 of 2). (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Virginia studs--18th century. (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Schedule of the twenty-six principal ante-revolutionary Virginia studs. (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Early Kentucky pedigrees. (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Maryland horses, 1745-1771 (folder 1 of 2). (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Maryland horses, 1745-1771 (folder 2 of 2). (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Maryland horses, 1772-1783 (folder 1 of 3). (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Maryland horses, 1772-1783 (folder 2 of 3). (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Maryland horses, 1772-1783 (folder 3 of 3). (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Maryland horses, 1784-1812 (and later) (folder 1 of 3). (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Maryland horses, 1784-1812 (and later) (folder 2 of 3). (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Maryland horses, 1784-1812 (and later) (folder 3 of 3). (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Index of Maryland horses. (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - South Carolina horses. (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Carolina horses (duplicates). (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - South Carolina horses. (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - New Jersey pedigrees. (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Northern horses, 1780-1788, 1797. (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - American Stud Book entries--horses. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - American Stud Book entries--mares. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Obituaries of horses bred and owned in the United States (Bruce). (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - American bred colts entered by ASB as imported from England prior to 1776 (pp. 181-203 and 3 unnumbered pages). (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - American bred colts listed by Bruce as imported. (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Imported horses, 1730-1746 (folder 1 of 2). (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Imported horses, 1730-1746 (folder 2 of 2). (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Imported horses, 1747-1753 (folder 1 of 2). (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Imported horses, 1747-1753 (folder 2 of 2). (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Imported horses, 1754-1755. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Imported horses, 1756-1759 (folder 1 of 2). (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Imported horses, 1756-1759 (folder 2 of 2). (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Imported horses, 1760-1761 (folder 1 of 2). (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Imported horses, 1760-1761 (folder 2 of 2). (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Imported horses, 1762-1763 (folder 1 of 2). (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Imported horses, 1762-1763 (folder 2 of 2). (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Imported horses, 1764 (folder 1 of 2). (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Imported horses, 1764 (folder 2 of 2). (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Imported horses, 1765 (folder 1 of 2). (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Imported horses, 1765 (folder 2 of 2). (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Imported horses, 1766. (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Imported horses, 1767. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Imported horses, 1768-1772 (folder 1 of 2). (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Imported horses, 1768-1772 (folder 2 of 2). (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Imported horses, 1773 (folder 1 of 2). (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Imported horses, 1773 (folder 2 of 2). (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Imported horses, 1774-1782. (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Imported horses, 1783-1785 (folder 1 of 2). (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Imported horses, 1783-1785 (folder 2 of 2). (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Imported horses, 1786-1790 (folder 1 of 2). (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Imported horses, 1786-1790 (folder 2 of 2). (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Imported horses, 1791-1792 (folder 1 of 2). (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Imported horses, 1791-1792 (folder 2 of 2). (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Imported horses, 1793-1794. (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Imported horses, 1795. (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Imported horses, 1796 (folder 1 of 2). (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Imported horses, 1796 (folder 2 of 2). (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Imported horses, 1797 (folder 1 of 3). (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Imported horses, 1797 (folder 2 of 3). (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Imported horses, 1797 (folder 3 of 3). (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Imported horses, 1798 (folder 1 of 2). (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Imported horses, 1798 (folder 2 of 2). (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Imported horses, 1799 (folder 1 of 2). (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Imported horses, 1799 (folder 2 of 2). (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Imported horses, 1800-1801 (folder 1 of 2). (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Imported horses, 1800-1801 (folder 2 of 2). (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Imported horses, 1802. (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Imported horses, A-O, 1803. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Imported horses, P-W, 1803. (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Imported horses, 1804-1805. (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Imported horses, 1806-1811. (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Imported horses, 1812-1820. (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Imported horses, 1821-1835 (folder 1 of 2). (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Imported horses, 1821-1835 (folder 2 of 2). (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Imported horses after 1830. (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Imported horses, 1784-1830. (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Imported horses--obituaries. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Virginia imported horses. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Imported horses index. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Imported horses index. (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Bruce's entries of horses imported before the Revolution (folder 1 of 2). (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Bruce's entries of horses imported before the Revolution (folder 2 of 2). (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Bruce's entries of horses imported after the Revolution (folder 1 of 2). (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Bruce's entries of horses imported after the Revolution (folder 2 of 2). (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Bruce--imported horses--obituaries after 1830. (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Imported mares, 1733-1759 (folder 1 of 2). (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Imported mares, 1733-1759 (folder 2 of 2). (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Imported mares, 1760-1774 (folder 1 of 3). (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Imported mares, 1760-1774 (folder 2 of 3). (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Imported mares, 1760-1774 (folder 3 of 3). (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Imported mares, 1784-1830 (folder 1 of 4). (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Imported mares, 1784-1830 (folder 2 of 4). (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Imported mares, 1784-1830 (folder 3 of 4). (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Imported mares, 1784-1830(folder 4 of 4). (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Bruce's entries of mares imported before the Revolution. (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Bruce's entries of mares imported after the Revolution. (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Imported mares after 1830, A-E. (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Imported mares after 1830, F-O (folder 1 of 2). (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Imported mares after 1830, F-O (folder 2 of 2). (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Imported mares after 1830, P-Z (folder 1 of 2). (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Imported mares after 1830, P-Z (folder 2 of 2). (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Sources of mares' names. (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Mares--miscellaneous. (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - English stallions in England, 1743-1774 (folder 1 of 2, A-N). (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - English stallions in England, 1743-1774 (folder 2 of 2, O-T). (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - English stallions in America before 1776 (folder 1 of 2--part 1). (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - English stallions in America before 1776 (folder 2 of 2--parts 2-4). (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - English bred horses in America before 1776 (folder 1 of 2--A-O, pp. 3-101). (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - English bred horses in America before 1776 (folder 2 of 2--P-Y, pp. 102-164). (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Mythological entries in ASB of colts therein recorded as imported from England prior to 1776 (pp. 165-180). (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Importers of two or more English horses, 1784-1830. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Imported English and Irish horses. (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - English bred horses in America before 1776. (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Canadian horses. (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Research on French Horses. (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Spanish and Oriental stock, 1740-1830. (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Oriental horses in America before 1776. (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Bruce--imported Arabian horses after 1830. (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Arabians and Barbs. (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Eaton's Arabians. (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Index of horses and mares. (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Entries from American Stud Book (starts at Antaeus). (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Entries from American Stud Book (starts at Antaeus). (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Entries from American Stud Book (starts at Antaeus). (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Entries from American Stud Book (starts at Americus). (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Entries from American Stud Book (starts at Americus--incomplete). (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Entries from American Stud Book (starts at Dormouse). (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Entries from American Stud Book (starts at Dormouse). (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Entries from American Stud Book (starts at Dormouse). (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Entries from American Stud Book (starts at Dormouse--incomplete). (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous notes on horses (folder 1 of 2). (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous notes on horses (folder 2 of 2). (Box 18, Folder 11)
- Series II: Individuals and families., Extent: 6 boxes. (Box 19-24)
  - Alexander (Lord Stirling). (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Alston of South Carolina (Alston's Slouch). (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Ambler. (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Baird. (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Banister. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - John Baylor I. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - John Baylor II. (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - John Baylor letters. (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Beckwith. (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Bland. (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Booth (the Janus stock). (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Braxton. (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Brodnax. (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Burwell. (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Byrd. (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Carlyle. (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Carroll of Carrollton. (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Carter. (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Cary. (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Churchill. (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Clarke. (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - John Parke Custis. (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Daingerfield. (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Dandridge. (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - DeLancey. (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Dulany. (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Dunlop. (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Duval. (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Edgar. (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Evans. (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Evans. (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Fairfax. (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - The Fenwicks (folder 1 of 3). (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - The Fenwicks (folder 2 of 3). (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - The Fenwicks (folder 3 of 3). (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Fenwick. (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Fenwick--John's Island--Fenwick will. (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Fitzhugh. (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Gist. (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Lord Godolphin's stud book. (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Goode. (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Gower. (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Hamilton of Maryland. (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Harrison of Berkeley. (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Harrison of Brandon. (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Hart and McDonald. (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Heard of New Jersey. (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Hiltzheimer. (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Hoomes of the Bowling Green. (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Hoomes and others. (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Hunter. (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Benjamin Hyde of Fredericksburg. (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - James Jackson of Alabama. (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - T. Jefferson. (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - W. R. Johnson. (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Lee. (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Lightfoot. (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Lloyd. (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - Ludwell. (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - Maryland Jockey Club. (Box 21, Folder 22)
  - Mayle. (Box 21, Folder 23)
  - McCarty. (Box 21, Folder 24)
  - McNaught. (Box 21, Folder 25)
  - Meade. (Box 21, Folder 26)
  - Mercer. (Box 21, Folder 27)
  - Moore of Cape Fear. (Box 21, Folder 28)
  - Morton. (Box 21, Folder 29)
  - Nelson. (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Norris of Pennsylvania. (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Ogle. (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Page. (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Lord Portmore. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Randolph of Roanoke. (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - John Randolph correspondence. (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - John Randolph correspondence--transcripts. (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - [John] Randolph's advertisements. (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - [John Randolph] Coalter's exr. vs. Bryan. (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - [John Randolph] Sale of the Randolph stud. (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Randolphiana. (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - John Randolph of Charleston. (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Ritchie. (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Ruffin. (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Selden. (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - James Seymour. (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - Sharpe. (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - Shy. (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - Meriwether Smith. (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - Spotswood. (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - Spotswood (Apollo's Dam. (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - Syme. (Box 22, Folder 23)
  - Talmadge of Connecticut. (Box 22, Folder 24)
  - Tasker. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Tasker (Selima). (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Tasker (other than Selima). (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Tayloe. (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Sir John Temple. (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Thacker. (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Thornton. (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Tyler. (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - E. V. Valentine. (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Wadsworth of Connecticut. (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Walstenholme. (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - G. Washington. (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Williamson. (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Willis. (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Wormeley. (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Virginia families, A-B. (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Virginia families, C-D. (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Virginia families, E-G. (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Virginia families, H-L. (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Virginia families, M-P. (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Virginia families, R-S. (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Virginia families, T-Y. (Box 24, Folder 4)
- Series III: Advertisements., Extent: 3 boxes. (Box 24-26)
  - Virginia Gazette advertisements, 1766-1775. (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Virginia Gazette advertisements, 1776-1777. (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Virginia Gazette advertisements, 1778. (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Virginia Gazette advertisements, 1779. (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Virginia Gazette advertisements, 1780-1781. (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Virginia Gazette advertisements (folder 1 of 2). (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Virginia Gazette advertisements (folder 2 of 2). (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Virginia Gazette and American Advertiser advertisements, 1785-1786. (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Virginia Gazette and Richmond and Manchester Advertiser advertisements, 1794-1796. (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Virginia Gazette and Petersburg Intelligencer advertisements, 1795-1796. (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Petersburg Intelligencer and Republican horses at stud, 1801-1803. (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Petersburg Intelligencer advertisements, 1811-1818. (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Petersburg Intelligencer advertisements, 1811-1818. (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - The Intelligencer and Petersburg Commercial Advertiser advertisements. (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Virginia Argus advertisements, 1797-1801. (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Virginia Herald and Fredericksburg and Falmouth Advertiser advertisements, 1795-1797. (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Virginia Herald advertisements, 1799. (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Republican Citizen and Farmer and Planter's Chronicle advertisements, 1797. (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Republican Journal and Dumfries Weekly Advertiser advertisements, 1796. (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Virginia newspaper advertisements, 1787-1834. (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Maryland Gazette advertisements, 1749-1772. (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Maryland Gazette advertisements, 1778-1783. (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Federal Gazette and Baltimore Daily Advertiser advertisements, 1798-1803. (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - Federal Gazette and Baltimore Daily Advertiser advertisements, 1798-1803 (duplicates). (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - North Carolina Gazette advertisements, 1775-1778. (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - Raleigh Register and North Carolina Gazette advertisements, 1809. (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - North Carolina advertisements, 1793-1823. (Box 25, Folder 20)
  - North Carolina advertisements (duplicate). (Box 25, Folder 21)
  - South Carolina advertisements, part I with index, 1760-1779 (folder 1 of 2). (Box 25, Folder 22)
  - South Carolina advertisements, part I, 1760-1779 (folder 2 of 2). (Box 25, Folder 23)
  - South Carolina advertisements, part II, 1778-1812 (folder 1 of 2). (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - South Carolina advertisements, part II, 1778-1812 (foder 2 of 2). (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Georgia advertisements, with index, 1763-1800. (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Gleanings from Philadelphia newspapers, 1788-1801. (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Advertisements in out-of-state newspapers (Maryland and north), 1790-1793. (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Out-of-state advertisements. (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Horses--advertisements. (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Advertisements--list of newspapers. (Box 26, Folder 8)
- Series IV: Racing., Extent: 2 boxes. (Box 26-27)
  - Virginia racing calendar ante 1774. (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Virginia racing calendar (incomplete), 1785-1825 (folder 1 of 2). (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Virginia racing calendar (incomplete), 1785-1825 (folder 2 of 2). (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Racing notes, Norfolk Herald, 1796-1802. (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Petersburg Intelligencer and Republican advertisements of races, 1801-1803. (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Racing notes, Petersburg Intelligencer, 1804-1808. (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Racing in Washington, 1796-1812. (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - Maryland racing calendar, 1749-1772. (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - Notes on racing in Maryland newspapers, 1782-1803. (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - Selima Stakes, 1925, 1928. (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - Races in Pennsylvania, New Jersey, and New York. (Box 26, Folder 19)
  - Advertisements of races to come, 1779-1804 (folder 1 of 2). (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Advertisements of races to come, 1779-1804 (folder 2 of 2). (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Advertisements of races to come, 1805-1824 (folder 1 of 2). (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Advertisements of races to come, 1805-1824 (folder 2 of 2). (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Racing notes, 1788-1824. (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - American subscribers to the Racing Calendars before organization of the American Jockey Club, 1866. (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Racing in Virginia. (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Index of Horses Names--Cheney's 1744 Racing Calendar (negative photostats). (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Index of Horses Names--Cheney's 1744 Racing Calendar (positive photostats). (Box 27, Folder 9)
- Series V: Publications., Extent: 3 boxes. (Box 27-29)
  - The John's Island Stud. (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - The John's Island Stud--proofs. (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - The John's Island Stud--gallies. (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - The John's Island Stud--special gallies. (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - The John's Island Stud--plates. (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - The John's Island Stud--images. (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - American Turf Register--Memoir of Sir Archy, vol. 1, pp. 164-167. (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - American Turf Register--entries on John Randolph, vol. 1, pp. 313, 381-382, 417, 461-462. (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - American Turf Register--Rural Sports--Hawking in America, vol. 2, pp. 28-29. (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - American Turf Register--William R. Johnson, vol. 3, pp. 519-522, vol. 4, pp. 9-12. (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - American Turf Register--John Randolph of Roanoke, vol. 4, pp. 573-578, 622-628. (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - American Turf Register--Sale of Part of the Stud of the Late Hon. John Randolph of Roanoke, vol. 6, pp. 248-250. (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - American Turf Register--Horses of the Olden Time, vol. 7, pp. 363-365. (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - American Turf Register--An American Sketch of a True Sportsman, vol. 7, p. 368. (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - American Turf Register--A. J. Davis, vol. 9, pp. 12-13, 187-188, vol. 11, pp. 47, 100, 154, 241-243, 324-326, 366, 371-372, 475-476, 559-560. (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - American Turf Register--The Godolphin Arabian, vol. 10, pp. 25-30, 448-454. (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - American Turf Register--The Sporting Reminiscences of the Late Dr. T., vol. 10, pp. 427-429, 527-528. (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - American Turf Register--List of Blood Stock, vol. 11, pp. 12-13, 142-144, 187-188. (Box 28, Folder 12)